<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM)</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/cclm/63/10/html" rel="via"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/cclm.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/cclm/html" rel="related"/>
  <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161578+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/cclm.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM)</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Frontmatter</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter10/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter10</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161600+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter10</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quality indicators: an evolving target for laboratory medicine</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0674/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0674</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161607+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Mario Plebani
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0674</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Regulating the future of laboratory medicine: European regulatory landscape of AI-driven medical device software in laboratory medicine</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0482/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0482</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161614+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hikmet Can Çubukçu, Guilaine Boursier, Solveig Linko, Francisco A. Bernabeu-Andreu, Pika Meško Brguljan, Katerina Tosheska-Trajkovska, Duilio Brugnoni, Neda Milinkovic, Andrea Padoan, Marc Thelen, on behalf of the European Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (EFLM) Division: Quality, Standards and Regulations, Committee on Accreditation and ISO/CEN standards (C: A/ISO)
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0482</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The spectrum of nuclear patterns with stained metaphase chromosome plate: morphology nuances, immunological associations, and clinical relevance</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0286/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0286</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161623+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Wilson de Melo Cruvinel, Guilherme Guerra Ferreira, Lais Laura de Souza, Wilson da Costa Veloso Neto, Clayson Moura Gomes, Paulo Luiz Carvalho Francescantonio, Luis Eduardo Coelho Andrade
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0286</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Comprehensive assessment of medical laboratory performance: a 4D model of quality, economics, velocity, and productivity indicators</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0323/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0323</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161629+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Pavel S. Zubanov, Pavel P. Tregub, Arkady S. Goldberg, Mikhail A. Godkov, Vasily G. Akimkin
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0323</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Detecting cardiac injury: the next generation of high-sensitivity cardiac troponins improving diagnostic outcomes</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0418/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0418</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161635+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Giuseppe Lippi, Carl J. Lavie, Fabian Sanchis-Gomar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0418</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Can Theranos resurrect from its ashes?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0651/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0651</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161640+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Miyo K. Chatanaka, Eleftherios P. Diamandis, Mario Plebani
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0651</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Australasian guideline for the performance of sweat chloride testing 3rd edition: to support cystic fibrosis screening, diagnosis and monitoring</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0433/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0433</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161645+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by John Massie, Avis McWhinney, Lawrence Greed, Natasha Robbins, Peter Graham, Natasha Heather, Carol Wai-Kwan Siu, Eric Law, Ronda F. Greaves, On behalf of the AACB-RCPAQAP Advisory Committee for Inborn Errors and in association with the IFCC Committee Emerging Technologies in Paediatric Laboratory Medicine
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0433</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recommendations for the integration of standardized quality indicators for glucose point-of-care testing</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0448/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0448</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161651+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Julie L.V. Shaw, Saranya Arnoldo, Ihssan Bouhtiany, Davor Brinc, Miranda Brun, Christine Collier, Anna Fuezery, Angela W.S. Fung, Yun Huang, Sukhbir Kaur, Michael Knauer, Elie Kostantin, Lyne Labrecque, Felix Leung, Vinita Thakur, Allison Venner, Paul Yip, Vincent De Guire
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0448</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A cost-effective assessment for the combination of indirect immunofluorescence and solid-phase assay in ANA-screening</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0170/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0170</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161663+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Nicoletta Gallo, Giulia Musso, Mario Plebani
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0170</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Assessment of measurement uncertainty of immunoassays and LC-MS/MS methods for serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0554/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0554</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161669+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Etienne Cavalier, Harjit P. Bhattoa, Annemieke C. Heijboer, Giovanni Lombardi, Vincent Delatour, Katleen Van Uytfanghe, Konstantinos Makris, Niklas Rye Jørgensen, Markus Herrmann, Richard Pikner, Pierre Lukas, Samuel D. Vasikaran, Callum G. Fraser, On behalf of the IFCC-IOF Committee on Bone Metabolism
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0554</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A novel immunoprecipitation-based targeted liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry analysis for accurate determination for copeptin in human serum</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0022/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0022</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161676+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Danni Mu, Xiaoli Ma, Yichen Ma, Danchen Wang, Yutong Zou, Ying Zhu, Jian Zhong, Dandan Sun, Yicong Yin, Yumeng Gao, Yuemeng Li, Shi Chen, Huijuan Zhu, Songlin Yu, Ling Qiu, Xinqi Cheng
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0022</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Histamine metabolite to basal serum tryptase ratios in systemic mastocytosis and hereditary alpha tryptasemia using a validated LC-MS/MS approach</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0189/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0189</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161682+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Abdulrazzaq Alheraky, Claude P. Van Der Ley, Martijn Van Faassen, Saskia K. Klein, Hanneke N.G. Oude Elberink, Caroline Roozendaal, Michel J. Vos, André B. Mulder, Ido P. Kema
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0189</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Machine learning algorithms with body fluid parameters: an interpretable framework for malignant cell screening in cerebrospinal fluid</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0302/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0302</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161687+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Xianfei Ye, Xinfeng Zhao, Yinyu Lou, Hanqi Pan, Yunying Chen
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0302</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impact of analytical bias on machine learning models for sepsis prediction using laboratory data</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0491/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0491</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161693+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Meryem Rumeysa Yesil, Ilaria Talli, Michela Pelloso, Chiara Cosma, Elisa Pangrazzi, Mario Plebani, Yasemin Ustundag, Andrea Padoan
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0491</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Immunochemical measurement of urinary free light chains and Bence Jones proteinuria</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0265/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0265</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161698+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Laura Michetti, Rudi Ravasio, Roberto Marozzi, Ester Antelmi, Arianna Ghirardi, Greta Bolzoni
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0265</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Serum biomarkers as early indicators of outcomes in spontaneous subarachnoid hemorrhage</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0309/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0309</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161704+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Anna Maria Auricchio, Giulia Napoli, Giovanni Maria Ceccarelli, Renata Martinelli, Grazia Menna, Marco Obersnel, Luca Scarcia, Andrea Urbani, Alessandro Olivi, Giuseppe Maria Della Pepa, Silvia Baroni
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0309</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>High myoglobin plasma samples risk being reported as falsely low due to antigen excess – follow up after a 2-year period of using a mitigating procedure</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0409/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0409</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161710+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Anders O. Olsson, Karin Lundberg, Esmira Becirevic, Malin Stenberg, Joakim Sandstedt
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0409</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Commutability evaluation of glycated albumin candidate EQA materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0507/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0507</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161715+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Rui Wu, Huijuan Zhou, Xiaerbanu Nizhamnuding, Anqi Pan, Hao Zheng, Jiangtao Zhang, Haijian Zhao, Jing Wang, Tianjiao Zhang, Chuanbao Zhang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0507</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health-related reference intervals for heavy metals in non-exposed young adults</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0076/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0076</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161721+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Chiara Di Resta, Francesco Paleari, Assunta Naclerio, Floriana Iannace, Roberto Leone, Ivan Shashkin, Marco Fumagalli, Chiara Sacco, Lucia Bellocchi, Massimo Locatelli, Giuseppe Banfi, Paola M.V. Rancoita, Rossella Tomaiuolo
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0076</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Practical handling of hemolytic, icteric and lipemic samples for coagulation testing in European laboratories. A collaborative survey from the European Organisation for External Quality Assurance Providers in Laboratory Medicine (EQALM)</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0319/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0319</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161730+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Ann Helen Kristoffersen, Martine J. Hollestelle, Janne Cadamuro, Andreas Hillarp, Ian Jennings, Rachel Marrington, Gro Gidske, Dagmar Kesseler, Piet Meijer
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0319</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Assessment of atypical cells in detecting bladder cancer in female patients</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0268/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0268</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161736+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Yan Zhao, Enhao Zhang, Yinling Wang, Jun Zheng, Danning Jin, Hong Luan
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0268</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>False-positive cardiac troponin I values due to macrotroponin in healthy athletes after COVID-19</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0427/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0427</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161741+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Angelika Hammerer-Lercher, Christine K. Kissel, Saara Wittfooth, Helea Junes, Emel Kaplan, Gabrielle Huré, Alessandra Sanzone, Peter Neyer, Luca Bernasconi, Robert Manka, Patrik Noack, Daniëlle Hof, Ola Hammarsten, Christian Mueller
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0427</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A comparison of current methods to measure antibodies in type 1 diabetes</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0238/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0238</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161753+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Maria Infantino, Mariangela Manfredi, Emirena Garrafa, Silvia Pancani, Anastasia Lechiara, Emanuela Maria Mobilia, Valentina Grossi, Barbara Lari, Nicola Bizzaro, Giampaola Pesce
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0238</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The neglected issue of pyridoxal- 5′ phosphate</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0550/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0550</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161758+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Carmen Ricós, Maria Carmen Perich, M. Pilar Fernandez-Calle
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0550</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Error in prostate-specific antigen levels after prostate cancer treatment with radical prostatectomy</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0430/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0430</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161764+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Remy J.H. Martens, Bart E.P.B. Ballieux, Ronald Bos, Floris Helmich
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0430</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Arivale is dead ‒ Hooke is alive</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0443/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0443</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161769+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Miyo K. Chatanaka, Eleftherios P. Diamandis
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0443</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A single dose of 20-mg of ostarine is detectable in hair</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0633/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0633</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161774+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Jean-Claude Alvarez, Isabelle Etting
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0633</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Growing importance of vocabularies in medical laboratories</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0545/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0545</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161779+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Marco Pradella
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0545</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>62nd National Congress of the Hungarian Society of Laboratory Medicine Szeged, Hungary, August 28–30, 2025</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0856/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0856</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T13:40:44.161784+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0856</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
