<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM)</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/cclm/63/7/html" rel="via"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/cclm.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/cclm/html" rel="related"/>
  <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289336+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/cclm.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM)</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Frontmatter</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter7/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter7</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289355+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-frontmatter7</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The journey to pre-analytical quality</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0057/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0057</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289360+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Mario Plebani
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0057</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Manual tilt tube method for prothrombin time: a commentary on contemporary relevance</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0157/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0157</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289367+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Emmanuel J. Favaloro
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0157</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From errors to excellence: the pre-analytical journey to improved quality in diagnostics. A scoping review</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1277/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1277</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289372+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by George K. John, Emmanuel J. Favaloro, Samantha Austin, Md Zahidul Islam, Abishek B. Santhakumar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1277</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Advancements and challenges in high-sensitivity cardiac troponin assays: diagnostic, pathophysiological, and clinical perspectives</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1090/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1090</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289378+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Aldo Clerico, Martina Zaninotto, Alberto Aimo, Andrea Padoan, Claudio Passino, Antonio Fortunato, Claudio Galli, Mario Plebani
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1090</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Is it feasible for European laboratories to use SI units in reporting results?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0113/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0113</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289383+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Martina Zaninotto, Luisa Agnello, Lora Dukic, Tomáš Šálek, Anna Linko-Parvinen, Tejas Kalaria, Pieter Vermeersch, On Behalf of European Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (EFLM) Committee-Harmonization (C-H) and Committee-Postanalytical Phase (C-POST)
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0113</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What does cancer screening have to do with tomato growing?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1408/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1408</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289391+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Miyo K. Chatanaka, Eleftherios P. Diamandis
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1408</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Computer simulation approaches to evaluate the interaction between analytical performance characteristics and clinical (mis)classification: a complementary tool for setting indirect outcome-based analytical performance specifications</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1195/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1195</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289396+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hikmet Can Çubukçu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1195</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Artificial base mismatches-mediated PCR (ABM-PCR) for detecting clinically relevant single-base mutations</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-0962/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-0962</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289401+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Cia-Hin Lau, Kejiang Guo, Gang Chen, Minghai Zou, Zhongqi Zhou, Tao Wang, Zhihao Huang, Jiaqi Li, Wenjiao Dong, Yumei Huang, Pik Kwan Lo, Hongman Xue, Xiaojun Huang, Meijing Xu, Chung Tin, Haibao Zhu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-0962</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Antiphospholipid IgG Certified Reference Material ERM®-DA477/IFCC: a tool for aPL harmonization?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0032/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0032</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289406+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Claudia Grossi, Liesbet Deprez, Caterina Bodio, Maria Orietta Borghi, Suresh Kumar, Nicola Pozzi, Paolo Macor, Silvia Piantoni, Angela Tincani, Massimo Radin, Savino Sciascia, Gustavo Martos, Evanthia Monogioudi, Ingrid Zegers, Joanna Sheldon, Rohan Willis, Pier Luigi Meroni
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0032</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>External quality assessment of the manual tilt tube technique for prothrombin time testing: a report from the IFCC-SSC/ISTH Working Group on the Standardization of PT/INR</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1446/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1446</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289411+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Claudia van Rijn, Charmane Abdoel, Shanti Baktawar, Petra Herbel, Anja Jünschke, Michelle Bryant, Steve Kitchen, Erica Scalambrino, Marigrazia Clerici, Anne Stavelin, Piet Meijer, Christa M. Cobbaert, Antonius M.H.P. van den Besselaar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1446</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Simple steps to achieve harmonisation and standardisation of dried blood spot phenylalanine measurements and facilitate consistent management of patients with phenylketonuria</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1367/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1367</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289416+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Rachel S. Carling, Zoe Barclay, Nathan Cantley, Nana Ghansah, Sarah L. Hogg, Alistair Horman, Stuart J. Moat, Simon Cowen, Chris Hopley, Chloe Deaves, Emily Whyte
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1367</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Inclusion of pyridoxine dependent epilepsy in expanded newborn screening programs by tandem mass spectrometry: set up of first and second tier tests</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1230/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1230</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289422+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Roberta Damiano, Maria Della Bona, Elena Procopio, Renzo Guerrini, Alessandra Bettiol, Giancarlo la Marca
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1230</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analytical performance evaluation and optimization of serum 25(OH)D LC-MS/MS measurement</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1416/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1416</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289427+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Weiyan Zhou, Meiliang Gong, Yuanli Mao, Xiaofen Yuan, Yuhang Deng, Qianwen Zhang, Wei Guo, Ling Qiu, Xianzhang Huang, Zheng Cao, Jun Xia, Xuhui She, Yulong Cong, Chuanbao Zhang, Huafen Liu, Wenxiang Chen
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1416</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Towards routine high-throughput analysis of fecal bile acids: validation of an enzymatic cycling method for the quantification of total bile acids in human stool samples on fully automated clinical chemistry analyzers</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1414/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1414</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289431+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Angelique Masetto, Tina Leber, Tobias Frömel, Christoph Peter, Kai Prager, Matthias Grimmler
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1414</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analytical and clinical evaluations of Snibe Maglumi®S100B assay</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1508/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1508</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289436+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Samy Kahouadji, Laure Picard, Valentin Bailly Defrance, Bruno Pereira, Damien Bouvier, Jean-Baptiste Bouillon-Minois, Vincent Sapin
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1508</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prevalence and detection of citrate contamination in clinical laboratory</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1389/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1389</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289441+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Nathan Lorde, Rousseau Gama, Tejas Kalaria
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1389</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Temporal dynamics in laboratory medicine: cosinor analysis and real-world data (RWD) approaches to population chronobiology</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1198/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1198</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289445+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Fernando Marques-Garcia, Cristina Martinez-Bravo, Xavier Tejedor-Ganduxe, Ruben Fossion
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1198</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Establishing sex- and age-related reference intervals of serum glial fibrillary acid protein measured by the fully automated lumipulse system</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0093/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0093</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289449+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Luisa Agnello, Caterina Maria Gambino, Anna Maria Ciaccio, Rosaria Vincenza Giglio, Concetta Scazzone, Martina Tamburello, Giuseppina Candore, Giulia Accardi, Anna Aiello, Fabio Del Ben, Marcello Ciaccio
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0093</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Performance of the automated digital cell image analyzer UIMD PBIA in white blood cell classification: a comparative study with sysmex DI-60</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1323/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1323</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289454+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hongkyung Kim, Oh Joo Kweon, Sumi Yoon, Yong Kwan Lim, Bohyun Kim
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1323</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Flow-cytometric MRD detection in pediatric T-ALL: a multicenter AIEOP-BFM consensus-based guided standardized approach</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1503/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1503</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289459+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Michaela Reiterová, Saskia Kohlscheen, Oscar Maglia, Simona Sala, Angela Schumich, Margarita Maurer-Granofszky, Giovanni Faggin, Pamela Scarparo, Elena Varotto, Zuzana Šestáková, Peter Švec, Tamar Feuerstein, Helly Vernitsky, Daniela Kužílková, Ondřej Hrušák, Barbara Buldini, Michael Dworzak, Monika Brüggemann, Giuseppe Gaipa, Tomáš Kalina, On behalf of the AIEOP-BFM ALL Flow group
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1503</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impact of biological and genetic features of leukemic cells on the occurrence of “shark fins” in the WPC channel scattergrams of the Sysmex XN hematology analyzers in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0115/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0115</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289467+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Margot Egger, I-Fei Fang, Franz Quehenberger, Christoph Robier
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0115</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Assessing the clinical applicability of dimensionality reduction algorithms in flow cytometry for hematologic malignancies</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0017/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0017</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289473+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Min-Seung Park, Jong Kwon Lee, Boram Kim, Hee Young Ju, Keon Hee Yoo, Chul Won Jung, Hee-Jin Kim, Hyun-Young Kim
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0017</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evaluation of sex-specific 0-h high-sensitivity cardiac troponin T thresholds for the risk stratification of non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1118/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1118</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289478+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Ailun Zhang, Guorong Gu, Jing Zhu, Wenqi Shao, Jing Yang, Baishen Pan, Beili Wang, Chenling Yao, Wei Guo
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1118</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The first case of Teclistamab interference with serum electrophoresis and immunofixation</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0446/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0446</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289488+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Kamran Kadkhoda, Beth Faiman, Jason Valent, Samer Albahra, Nicole Boyert
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0446</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Is this quantitative test fit-for-purpose?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0194/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0194</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289493+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Arne Åsberg, Bjørn Johan Bolann
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0194</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reply to “Is this quantitative test fit-for-purpose?”</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0291/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0291</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289497+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Sarah J. Lord, Andrea Rita Horvath, Phillip J. Monaghan, Sverre Sandberg, Patrick M. Bossuyt, on behalf of the EFLM Committee, Clinical and Analytical Performance Specifications (C-CAPS)
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0291</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Short-term biological variation of coagulation and fibrinolytic measurands</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1479/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1479</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289502+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Martine J. Hollestelle, Ann Helen Kristoffersen, René N. Idema, Piet Meijer, Sverre Sandberg, Aasne K. Aarsand
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1479</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The first case of Teclistamab interference with serum electrophoresis and immunofixation</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0382/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0382</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289506+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Kamran Kadkhoda, Beth Faiman, Jason Valent, Samer Albahra, Nicole Boyert
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0382</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Imlifidase: a new interferent on serum protein electrophoresis looking as a rare plasma cell dyscrasia</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1467/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1467</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289510+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Veronica Davanzo, Sara Altinier, Irene Olimpo, Erica Nuzzolese, Lucrezia Furian, Daniela Basso
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1467</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Research on the development of image-based Deep Learning (DL) model for serum quality recognition</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1219/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1219</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289514+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Dongliang Man, Xiaotao Yang, Wei Du, Hanjia Ye, Yi Shi, Yifu Guan, Shuang Zhang, Ke Yun, Yuan Jiang, Xiaoxu Han, Hong Shang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1219</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Interference of hypertriglyceridemia on total cholesterol assay with the new CHOL2 Abbott method on Architect analyser</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2024-1441/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1441</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289519+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Mélina Terrasse, Denis Monneret, Laurent Desmurs, Fanny Zhao, Sabine Zaepfel, Mathilde Di Filippo, Régine Cartier, Oriane Marmontel
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2024-1441</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>10thAnnual Meeting of the Austrian Society for Laboratory Medicine and Clinical Chemistry (ÖGLMKC)</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/cclm-2025-0469/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0469</id>
    <updated>2025-05-29T04:53:44.289523+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2025-0469</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
