<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Open Chemistry</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/chem/23/1/html" rel="via"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/chem.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/chem/html" rel="related"/>
  <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194478+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/chem.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Open Chemistry</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Phytochemical investigation and evaluation of antioxidant and antidiabetic activities in aqueous extracts ofCedrus atlantica</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0121/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0121</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194496+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Amine Mounadi Idrissi, Mohamed Adil Mahraz, Soufiane Drioua, Amine Assouguem, Essam A. Ali, Mohamed A. Ibrahim, Chandra Mohan Mehta, Rachid Lahlali, Sara Tlemcani, Fatima Moussaoui, Ghizlan En-nabety, Noureddine Eloutassi, Amal Lahkimi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0121</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Influence of B4C addition on the tribological properties of bronze matrix brake pad materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0126/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0126</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194506+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hüsamettin Kuş
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0126</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Discovery of the bacterial HslV protease activators as lead molecules with novel mode of action</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0127/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0127</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194513+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Sana Aurangzeb, Muhammad Aurongzeb, Shahbaz Shamim, Yasmeen Rashid, Khalid Mohammed Khan, Tariq Aziz, Metab Alharbi, Abdullah F. Alasmari
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0127</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Characterization of volatile flavor compounds of cigar with different aging conditions by headspace–gas chromatography–ion mobility spectrometry</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0129/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0129</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194519+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Beibei Zhu, Jiaowen Chen, Guangfu Song, Yun Jia, Wanrong Hu, Hongyue An, Rongya Zhang, Zhiqiang Ma, Dongliang Li, Fang Xue
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0129</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective remediation of organic pollutant usingMusa acuminatapeel extract-assisted iron oxide nanoparticles</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0132/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0132</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194525+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Amor Hedfi, Manel Ben Ali, Sirajul Haq, Jamoliddin Razzokov, Wajid Rehman, Muhammad Waseem, Khaled Elmnasri, M. Khalid Hossain, Fazal Ur Rehman, Eldor Karimbaev, Shafia Shujaat
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0132</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analysis and health risk assessment of toxic elements in traditional herbal tea infusions</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0134/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0134</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194531+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Fuad A. Ababneh, Khaleel A. Abu-Sbeih
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0134</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cadmium exposure in marine crabs from Jiaxing City, China: Insights into health risk assessment</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0135/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0135</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194537+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Miao-hua Ge, Xiao-qiong Wu, Wei Xu, Xuan-zheng Wang, Xiang Zhang, Zhong-wen Chen
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0135</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green-synthesized silver nanoparticles ofCinnamomum zeylanicumand their biological activities</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0128/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0128</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194543+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Asia Noureen, Faisal Ahmad, Farhan Younas, Gezahign Fentahun Wondmie, Samir Ibenmoussa, Gamal A. Shazly, Mohammed Bourhia
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0128</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tetraclinis articulata(Vahl) Mast.,Mentha pulegiumL., andThymus zygisL. essential oils: Chemical composition, antioxidant and antifungal properties against postharvest fungal diseases of apple, andin vitro,in vivo, andin silicoinvestigation</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0131/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0131</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194549+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Faiza El Hajli, Said Chakir, Saoussan Annemer, Amine Assouguem, Fouzia Elaissaoui, Riaz Ullah, Essam A. Ali, Ravish Choudhary, Khalil Hammani, Rachid Lahlali, Ghizlane Echchgadda
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0131</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Exploration of plant alkaloids as potential inhibitors ofHIV–CD4 binding: Insight into comprehensivein silicoapproaches</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0130/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0130</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194555+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Imran Zafar, Zain Abbas, Sidra Abbas, Oluwagbade Joseph Odimayo, Qurat ul Ain, Turki M. Dawoud, Ousman B. Mahamat
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0130</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recovery of phenylethyl alcohol from aqueous solution by batch adsorption</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0136/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0136</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194561+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Elif Biçakci, Siddika Gamze Erzengin, Fatma Burcu Alp
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0136</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Electrochemical approach for monitoring the catalytic action of immobilized catalase</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0143/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0143</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194567+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Angel Peshkov, Merin Shukri, Mariya Pimpilova, Ilia Iliev, Nina Dimcheva
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0143</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesis of ZIF-8 for selective adsorption of dyes in water purification</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0140/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0140</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194572+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Zhengyao Zhang, Kui Sun, Yuqi Bao, Hong Lei, Jun Yang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0140</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Optimization of the conditions for the preparation of povidone iodine using the response surface methodology</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0144/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0144</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194578+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Ngoc Quy Nguyen, Tan Phat Dao, Minh Tien Nguyen, Xuan Tung Nguyen Tan, Kim Anh Le Thi, Khac Ky Lam, Nhi Yen Thi Tran
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0144</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A case study on the influence of soil amendment on ginger oil’s physicochemical properties, mineral contents, microbial load, and HPLC determination of its vitamin level</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0148/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0148</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194583+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Sarah Alharthi, Hilary Uguru, Nashi K. Alqahtani, Moses Onoziogie Akwenuke, Godspower I. Okolotu, Rokayya Sami, Roqayah H. Kadi, Woroud A. Alsanei, Sameer H. Qari
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0148</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Removal of antiviral favipiravir from wastewater using biochar produced from hazelnut shells</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0149/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0149</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194589+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Ayşegül Türk Baydır
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0149</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effect of biochar and soil amendment on bacterial community composition in the root soil and fruit of tomato under greenhouse conditions</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0147/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0147</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194595+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Jian Zhang, Rui Xia, Pengcheng Wang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0147</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bioremediation of malachite green dye usingSargassum wightiiseaweed and its biological and physicochemical characterization</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0137/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0137</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194601+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Kumaravel Kaliaperumal, Janeeba Aboobacker, Vigneshpriya Dhanapal, Abinaya Gayathri, Kumaran Subramanian, Arumugam Suresh, Sanniyasi Elumalai, Shobana Sampath, Sandhanasamy Devanesan, Mohamad S. AlSalhi, Perumal Asaithambi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0137</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evaluation of natural compounds as folate biosynthesis inhibitors inMycobacterium lepraeusing docking, ADMET analysis, and molecular dynamics simulation</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0145/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0145</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194607+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Abdullah R. Alanzi, Hattan A. Alharbi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0145</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Novel insecticidal properties of bioactive zoochemicals extracted from sea urchinSalmacis virgulata</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0141/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0141</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194614+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Karnan Ramachandran, Ramachandran Vinayagam, Usha Nandhini Govindan, Senthil Bakthavatchalam, Shunmuga Vadivu Ramalingam, Sukumaran Marimuthu, Abdurahman Hajinur Hirad, Zhi-Hong Wen, Sang Gu Kang, Yi-Hao Lo
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0141</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Elevational gradients shape total phenolic content and bioactive potential of sweet marjoram (Origanum majoranaL.): A comparative study across altitudinal zones</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0139/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0139</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194620+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Emel Karaca Öner, Meryem Yeşil, Sinem Aydın, Fatih Öner
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0139</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Study on the CO2absorption performance of deep eutectic solvents formed by superbase DBN and weak acid diethylene glycol</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0146/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0146</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194626+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Shihong Guo, Xuzhong Zhou, Chengfang Liu, Shuie Li
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0146</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preparation and wastewater treatment performance of zeolite-modified ecological concrete</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0151/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0151</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194631+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Zhiwu Liu, Xiaoyang Zhang, Shengbin Lai, Yonghe Yao, Xuyang Zhu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0151</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One-pot fabrication of highly porous morphology of ferric oxide-ferric oxychloride/poly-O-chloroaniline nanocomposite seeded on poly-1Hpyrrole: Photocathode for green hydrogen generation from natural and artificial seawater</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0123/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0123</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194637+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Mohamed Rabia, Maha Abdallah Alnuwaiser
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0123</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>High-efficiency photocathode for green hydrogen generation from sanitation water using bismuthyl chloride/poly-o-chlorobenzeneamine nanocomposite</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0112/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0112</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194642+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Eman Aldosari, Mohamed Rabia, Qinfang Zhang, S. H. Mohamed
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0112</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Comparative analysis of fruit quality parameters and volatile compounds in commercially grown citrus cultivars</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2024-0107/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0107</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194647+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Yakup Polat, Berken Cimen, Ferit Celik, Esra Ekşi, Gokmen Koc, Sezai Ercisli, Amine Assouguem, Kamal Aberkani, Zafar Iqbal, Chandra Mohan Mehta, Nesibe Ebru Kafkas
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2024-0107</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Total phenolic, flavonoid, flavonol, and tannin contents as well as antioxidant and antiparasitic activities of aqueous methanol extract ofAlhagi graecorumplant used in traditional medicine: Collected in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/chem-2025-0138/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0138</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T04:53:57.194654+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hossam M. Aljawdah, Mutee Murshed, Aiman A. Ammari, Mohammed Mares, Saleh Al-Quraishy
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2025-0138</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
