<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Green Processing and Synthesis</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/gps/14/1/html"/>
  <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530742+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Alexander Winkler</name>
    <uri>https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9145-7238</uri>
  </author>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/gps.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Green Processing and Synthesis</subtitle>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/gps.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>
  <entry>
    <title>Optimized green synthesis of silver nanoparticles from guarana seed skin extract with antibacterial potential</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2023-0210/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0210</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530762+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Rodrigo Botinelly Nogueira, Lizandro Manzato, Raiana Silveira Gurgel, Patrícia Melchionna Albuquerque, Fabiana Magalhães Teixeira Mendes, Dachamir Hotza
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0210</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green adsorbents for water remediation: Removal of Cr(vi) and Ni(ii) usingProsopis glandulosasawdust and biochar</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0197/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0197</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530770+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Syed Muhammad Salman, Safina Razzaq, Muhammad Adnan, Rozina, Sabiha Sultana, Asif Kamal, Abdullah Ahmed Al-Ghamdi, Dunia Abdel Aziz Al Farraj, Wajid Zaman
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0197</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green approach for the synthesis of zinc oxide nanoparticles from methanolic stem extract ofAndrographis paniculataand evaluation of antidiabetic activity:In silicoGSK-3β analysis</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0203/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0203</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530783+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Gopal Nithesh Kumar, Mohammad Ali, Bharathi Doddla Raghunathanaidu, Syed Sagheer Ahmed, Chandan Komalkumar, KM Doddi Hanumaiah Ananth Gowda, Chamanahalli Balaraju Prajwal, Faiyaz Shakeel
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0203</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Development of a green and rapid ethanol-based HPLC assay for aspirin tablets and feasibility evaluation of domestically produced bioethanol in Thailand as a sustainable mobile phase</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0200/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0200</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530789+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Thana Thanayutsiri, Siwa Mantadilok, Jiradet Sapsin, Thada Tungwattanaviboon, Jetsada Wongwatanasin, Praneet Opanasopit, Tanasait Ngawhirunpat, Theerasak Rojanarata
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0200</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A facile biodegradation of polystyrene microplastic byBacillus subtilis</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0153/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0153</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530795+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Norah Raqi Al-Otaibi, Promy Virk, Rasha Elsayim, Mohammed Elbagir Amin, Asma Mudhahi Alshammari, Alanoud Tariq Al Sudairi, Nada Ali Almohawis, Dalia Fouad, Manal A. Awad, Abdel-Basit Al-Odayni, Gadah Albasher
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0153</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Enhanced synthesis of fly ash-derived hydrated sodium silicate adsorbents via low-temperature alkaline hydrothermal treatment for advanced environmental applications</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0172/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0172</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530801+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Yeqing Zhu, Xiaojun Huang, Tianxiang Yu, Kun Liu, Meng Zhang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0172</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impact of metal nanoparticles biosynthesized using camel milk on bacterial growth and copper removal from wastewater</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0192/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0192</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530806+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Amal Mohamed Al-Mohaimeed, Maha Farouk El-Tohamy, Nadine Mohamad Safouh Moubayed
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0192</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preparation of Co/Cr-MOFs for efficient removal of fleroxacin and Rhodamine B</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0195/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0195</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530812+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Fuhua Wei, Yan Wang, Qinhui Ren, Qin Zhang, Hongliang Chen, Zhao Liang
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0195</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Applying nanocarbon prepared from coal as an anode in lithium-ion batteries</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0151/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0151</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530817+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Do Tra Huong, Nguyen Van Tu, Ha Xuan Linh, Nguyen Thi Hien Lan, Nguyen Quoc Dung, Chu Manh Nhuong, Nguyen Khanh Long, Truong Xuan Vuong, Thi Kim Ngan Tran
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0151</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improved electrochemical synthesis of Cu–Fe/brass foil alloy followed by combustion for high-efficiency photoelectrodes and hydrogen production in alkaline solutions</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0137/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0137</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530823+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Islam Kholidy, Mohammad H. BinSabt, H. M. Abd El-Salam, Mohamed Shaban, Mohamed Rabia
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0137</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Precipitation of terephthalic acid from post-consumer polyethylene terephthalate waste fractions</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2023-0244/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0244</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530828+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Clemens Müller, Dirk Wilhelm Franke-Hameke, Esther Laura Brepohl, Lars Biermann, Carsten Eichert, Stephan Scholl
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0244</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Biosynthesized zinc oxide nanoparticles: Multifunctional potential applications in anticancer, antibacterial, andB. subtilisDNA gyrase docking</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0218/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0218</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530834+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Samy Selim, Salem S. Salem, Medhat E. Owda, Mohammed S. Almuhayawi, Hattan S. Gattan, Mohammed H. Alruhaili, Amna A. Saddiq, Shaimaa Hussein, Mohammad M. Al-Sanea, Soad K. Al Jaouni
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0218</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anticancer and antimicrobial effects of green-synthesized silver nanoparticles usingTeucrium poliumleaves extract</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0227/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0227</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530842+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Reem M. Aljowaie, Ibrahim M. Aziz
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0227</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesis of eco-friendly bioplastics fromChlorellaandLithothamnionalgae for safe and sustainable solutions for food packaging</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0208/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0208</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530848+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Nahed Ahmed Hussien, Maria Kamaluldeen Salah Al-Deen, Muzun Saeed Al-zahrani, Shahad Fehaid Alwathnani, Rana Yahya Al-Sahli, Shatha Ruddah Albunyusi, Shahad Salem Al-Humayani, Samar Salman Alharthi, Mathael Faleh Almutairi, Fawz Fahad Algethami, Shouq Mohammed Alqurashi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0208</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Optimizing coal water slurry concentration via synergistic coal blending and particle size distribution</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0202/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0202</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530854+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Ming Liu, Hanxu Li
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0202</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesis of Ag@Cu and silver nanowire usingPterospermum heterophyllumextracts for surface-enhanced Raman scattering</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0028/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0028</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530859+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Khoa Tien Cao, Hue Thi Do
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0028</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles from Algerian propolis: Exploring biochemical, structural, antimicrobial, and anti-diabetic properties</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0222/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0222</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530865+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Halima Zidane, Ridha Ben Salem, Abdelkrim Rebiai, Ghayth Rigane, Djihad Chenna, Abdelatif Aouadi, Mohammad Al Diab Al Azzawi, Sabry Mohamed Attia, Sheikh Fayaz Ahmad, Maria Atanassova, Mohammed Messaoudi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0222</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Simultaneous quantification of mefenamic acid and paracetamol in fixed-dose combination tablet dosage forms using the green HPTLC method</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0251/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0251</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530871+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Prawez Alam, Faiyaz Shakeel, Mohammed Hamed Alqarni, Ahmed Ibrahim Foudah, Tariq Mohammed Aljarba, Fatma Mohamed Abdel Bar, Mohd Imran, Mohammad Ali
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0251</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesis of titanium dioxide nanoparticles using green tea (Camellia sinensis) extract: Characteristics and applications</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0226/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0226</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530876+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Thi Kim Ngan Tran, Le Khanh Van Tran, Ngoc Cat Thuyen Vo, Ngoc Cat Nguyen Vo, Thi Que Minh Doan, Hoang Danh Pham, Thi Nhu Dung Nguyen
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0226</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pharmaceutical properties for green fabricated ZnO and Ag nanoparticle-mediatedBorago officinalis:In silicopredications study</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0237/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0237</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530881+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Alyaa A. Alkhafaji, Hind M. Ahmed, Yasir B. Fadhil, Mina M. Allos, Majid S. Jabir, Duha S. Ahmed, Ali Abdullah Issa, Kin Weng Kong, Beng Fye Lau, Suresh Ghotekar, Ayman A. Swelum
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0237</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Synthesis and optimization of gemcitabine-loaded nanoparticles by using Box–Behnken design for treating prostate cancer:In vitrocharacterization andin vivopharmacokinetic study</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0188/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0188</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530888+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Muhammad Anjum Jamil, Furqan Muhammad Iqbal, Abdur Rehman Sarwar, Muhammad Omer Iqbal, Ahsan Arif, Abas O. Hadi, Muhammad Tayyab Gul, Aftab Ahmad, Nayla Munawar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0188</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A comparative analysis of single-step and multi-step methods for producing magnetic activated carbon from palm kernel shells: Adsorption of methyl orange dye</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0234/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0234</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530896+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Joko Waluyo, Farida Dwi Rahmawati, Muhammad Ghozy Izzulhaq, Ibnu Tryansar Purba, Mujtahid Kaavessina, Wusana Agung Wibowo, Sunu Herwi Pranolo, Haris Puspito Buwono, Ardie Septian, Muflih Arisa Adnan
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0234</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sustainable green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using walnut septum waste: Characterization and antibacterial properties</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0235/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0235</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530901+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Vlatka Gvozdić, Elvira Kovač-Andrić, Klara Kirchbaher, Ivan Ćorić, Zvonimir Užarević, Stela Jokić, Valentina Pavić
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0235</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Efficient electrocatalytic reduction of CO2to CO over Ni/Y diatomic catalysts</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0135/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0135</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530910+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Yujie Yan, Qiming Yu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0135</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sustainable innovations in garlic extraction: A comprehensive review and bibliometric analysis of green extraction methods</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0201/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0201</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530915+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Irianto Irianto, Suharmiati Suharmiati, Ahmad Syahmi Zaini, Muhammad Abbas Ahmad Zaini, Bramantyo Airlanngga, Nicky Rahmana Putra
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0201</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In situsupported rhodium catalyst on mesoporous silica for chemoselective hydrogenation of nitriles to primary amines</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/gps-2024-0193/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0193</id>
    <updated>2025-05-04T22:06:02.530921+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Abdelaziz Nait Ajjou, André Robichaud, Ateeq Rahman
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2024-0193</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
