<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Journal of Pediatric Endocrinology and Metabolism</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/jpem/38/4/html" rel="via"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/jpem.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/jpem/html" rel="related"/>
  <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814081+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/jpem.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Journal of Pediatric Endocrinology and Metabolism</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Frontmatter</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2025-frontmatter4/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2025-frontmatter4</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814100+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2025-frontmatter4</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Diabetes distress, depression, and future glycemic control among adolescents with type 1 diabetes</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0524/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0524</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814107+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Cecilia P. Damilano, K. Ming Chan Hong, Bethany A. Glick, Manmohan K. Kamboj, Robert P. Hoffman
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0524</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Is oxytocin related to psychiatric symptoms in adolescents with obesity?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0583/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0583</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814113+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Gonca Özyurt, Gönül Çatlı, Sezer Acar, Gülten Cingöz, Dua Özsoylu, Tuncay Küme, Sefa Kızıldağ, Bumin Nuri Dündar, Yusuf Öztürk, Ezgi Karagöz Tanıgör, Ali Evren Tufan, Ayhan Abaci
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0583</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Associations between body mass index and sleep duration in Brazilian children and adolescents: the moderating role of screen time</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0302/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0302</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814120+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Leticia Borfe, Ana P. Sehn, Cézane Priscila Reuter, Jorge Mota, Ryan Donald Burns, Caroline Brand, Anelise R. Gaya
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0302</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The transfer of care experience in young adults with type 1 diabetes</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0456/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0456</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814125+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by April Yerges, Yulia Semeniuk, Kimberly Vidmar, Rachel Stanek, Beth Van Den Langenberg, Aaron Carrel, Tracy Bekx
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0456</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Assessing the efficacy of a hybrid closed loop system in a racial-ethnic minority cohort of children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0535/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0535</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814129+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Andrea Granados, Juliana Orrego Castellanos, Andrea Martinez Sanchez, Maria Jose Giraldo, Adriana Carrillo-Iregui
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0535</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Do children with type 1 diabetes mellitus remain protected against hepatitis B?</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0520/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0520</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814133+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Pınar Yılmazbaş, Diğdem Bezen, Eren Vurgun
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0520</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Influence of excess weight on metabolic risk factors in Argentinian preschool children</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0513/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0513</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814138+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Agustina Malpeli, Virginia Stallings, Marisa Sala, María Victoria Fasano, Ana Varea, Liliana Disalvo, Natalia Matamoros, Andrea Tournier, Horacio F. Gonzalez
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0513</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Causal associations between childhood obesity and delayed puberty or height: a bidirectional two-sample Mendelian randomization study</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0438/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0438</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814146+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Lulu Cui, Ying Zhang, Ting Dong, Liya Xu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0438</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Differentiating true precocious puberty and puberty variants in consecutive 275 girls: a single center experience</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0467/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0467</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814154+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Emre Sarıkaya, Fatih Kilci
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0467</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Development of bone mineral density and content in children with cerebral palsy: a retrospective, longitudinal study</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0519/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0519</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814158+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Philipp Koebke, Leonie Schafmeyer, Bruno Lentzen, Titus Keller, Eckhard Schoenau, Ibrahim Duran
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0519</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Insights in non-CAH pediatric primary adrenal insufficiency: a single-center experience from India</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0476/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0476</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814162+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Aaditya Daga, Manjiri Karlekar, Anurag Lila, Vijaya Sarathi, Anima Sharma, Saba Samad Memon, Rohit Barnabas, Virendra Patil, Hemangini Thakker, Nalini Shah, Tushar Bandgar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0476</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effect of empagliflozin treatment on laboratory and clinical findings of patients with glycogen storage disease type Ib: first study from Türkiye</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0556/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0556</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814166+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Engin Köse, Figen Özçay, Halil İbrahim Aydın, Çiğdem Seher Kasapkara, Aslı İnci, Aynur Küçükcongar Yavaş, Leyla Tümer, Fatma Tuba Eminoğlu
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0556</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Clinical and laboratory characteristics of propionic acidemia in a Turkish cohort</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0366/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0366</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814171+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Halil Tuna Akar, Ayça Burcu Kahraman, Yılmaz Yıldız, Berat Baran, Kısmet Çıkı, Turgay Coşkun, Didem Yücel Yılmaz, Rıza Köksal Özgül, Hayrettin Hakan Aykan, Ali Dursun, Serap Sivri, Ayşegül Tokatlı
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0366</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on DKA severity in Black and White pediatric patients</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0526/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0526</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814180+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Shrina Patel, Elyzabeth Amador, Jonathan M. Fischell, Erin Bewley, Kaitlin Jeffries, Paula G. Newton, Stefanie Zaner Fischell
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0526</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evinacumab as an adjunct to lipid apheresis in an infant with homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0505/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0505</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814184+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Christian Stirnkorb, Verena Ney, Carsten Bergmann, Martin Bald
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0505</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DNA ligase IV deficiency identified in a patient with hypergonadotropic hypogonadism: a case report</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0510/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0510</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814188+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Deniz Yasar, Abdullah Sezer, Caner Aytekin, Gülin Karacan Küçükali, Beyhan Özkaya Dönmez, Aslıhan Araslı Yılmaz, İclal Okur, Behiye Sarıkaya Özdemir, Erdal Kurnaz, Melikşah Keskin, Şenay Savaş Erdeve
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0510</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moebius syndrome and hypopituitarism: a case of multiple pituitary hormone deficiency and revision of the literature</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/jpem-2024-0494/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0494</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:00:30.814193+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Silvia Molinari, Maria Laura Nicolosi, Angelo Selicorni, Chiara Fossati, Martina Lattuada, Iacopo Bellani, Federica Arcuti, Riccardo Carnevale, Andrea Biondi, Adriana Balduzzi, Alessandro Cattoni
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2024-0494</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
