<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Zeitschrift für Naturforschung C</title>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/znc/80/5-6/html" rel="via"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/znc.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/journal/key/znc/html" rel="related"/>
  <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398626+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/main/feed/znc.xml</id>
  <generator>https://github.com/alexander-winkler/degruyter_rss/blob/main/degruyter_feedgenerator.py</generator>
  <subtitle>A RSS feed containing the latest articles published in Zeitschrift für Naturforschung C</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Frontmatter</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2025-frontmatter5-6/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2025-frontmatter5-6</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398653+00:00</updated>
    <summary>DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2025-frontmatter5-6</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nourishment beyond grains: unveiling the multifaceted contributions of millets to United Nations Sustainable Development Goals</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0096/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0096</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398663+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Akash Kumar, Jhilam Pramanik, Aarzoo Jangra, Bhupendra Prajapati, Shiv Kumar, Rahul Mehra
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0096</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Exploring the functionality of fluorescent liposomes in cancer: diagnosis and therapy</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0144/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0144</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398673+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Bhupendra G. Prajapati, Jai Bharti Sharma, Ashutosh Pareek, Rahul Garg, Pushpendra Kumar Saini, Devesh U. Kapoor
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0144</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In vitroantibacterial activities, DPPH radical scavenging, and molecular simulation of isolated compounds from the leaves ofRhus ruspolii</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0127/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0127</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398682+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Tolessa Duguma, Yadessa Melaku, Daniel Rentsch, Akalu Terfa, Kebede Shenkute
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0127</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Characterization and antimicrobial activity of essential oils extracted from lemongrass (Cymbopogon flexuosus) using microwave-assisted hydro distillation</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0095/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0095</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398690+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Krishnendu Adhikary, Saurav Barman, Pradipta Banerjee, Pallav Mondal, Bomba Dam, Arijit Misra, Narayan Chandra Mandal, Debosmita Mukherjee, Bidyut Bandyopadhyay, Rajkumar Maiti
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0095</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In silicoDFT and molecular modeling of novel pyrazine-bearing thiazolidinone hybrids derivatives: elucidatingin vitroanti-cancer and urease inhibitors</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0103/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0103</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398699+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Shoaib Khan, Rafaqat Hussain, Yousaf Khan, Tayyiaba Iqbal, Saeed Anwar, Tariq Aziz, Metab Alharbi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0103</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Molecular mechanisms of the anticancer action of fustin isolated fromCotinus coggygriaScop. in MDA-MB-231 triple-negative breast cancer cell line</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0140/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0140</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398706+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Georgi G. Antov, Zlatina I. Gospodinova, Miroslav Novakovic, Vele Tesevic, Natalia A. Krasteva, Danail V. Pavlov, Stefka V. Valcheva-Kuzmanova
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0140</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green synthesized AgNPs of theAnchusa arvensisaqueous extract resulting in impressive protein kinase, antioxidant, antibacterial, and antifungal activities</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0148/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0148</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398715+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Mohamed Mohany, Jamshed Ali, Abdul Wahab, Fozia Fozia, Syed Majid Shah, Rukhsana Gul, Ahmad Gul, Ijaz Ahmad, Marija Milošević, Salim S. Al-Rejaie, Mourad A. M. Aboul-Soud
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0148</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Phytochemical composition, antimicrobial, antioxidant, and wound healing activities ofThermopsis turcica</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0102/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0102</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398730+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Gülçin Akdağ, Ömer Hazman, Laçine Aksoy, Mehmet Savrık, Ahmet Büyükben, Mustafa Abdullah Yılmaz, Oguz Cakir, Recep Kara
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0102</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Molecular detection ofCoxiella burnetiiinfection (Q fever) in livestock in Makkah Province, Saudi Arabia</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0126/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0126</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398742+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Hassan M. Baroom, Naser A. Alkenani, Bassam O. Al-Johny, Adi A. Almohimeed, Mohammed S. Mohammed, Layla A. Alshehri, Shaker S. Althobaiti, Raga I. Omar, Majed A. Alshaeri, Saleh M. Al-mmaqar
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0126</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Spermidine protects cellular redox status and ionic homeostasis in D-galactose induced senescence and natural aging rat models</title>
    <link href="https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/znc-2024-0181/html"/>
    <id>https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0181</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T05:07:55.398753+00:00</updated>
    <summary>Article by Sandeep Singh, Avnish Kumar Verma, Geetika Garg, Abhishek Kumar Singh, Syed Ibrahim Rizvi
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1515/znc-2024-0181</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
